So we've raised 1.1 billion dollars crowdfunding on
the internet. I don't go to wealthy people.
I don't go to Mark Cuban and say, hey fund
my project. I've never gone to a big equity fund
like a Blackstone and say give me a million
dollars. I could but I don't. I build a big
audience. I create great products and offers and then
I go to that audience and say would you guys
like to invest with me? What I do is I
compare myself to the amount of money on the planet.
There's 80 trillion dollars, 80 trillion bro
in circulation. That's US dollars. That's not
counting all the other bullshit currencies. So I'm like
man how do I get a tiny piece like just
a sniff, a whiff, a taste. Just let it visit
me for a second. And the only reason we believe a
million dollars a lot of money is because somebody told
you that it was a lot of money and the person
that told you it was a lot of money didn't
have a million dollars. The other thing is you got to
quit telling people you got money problems because if
you don't have any money, you don't have any
money. You don't have any money. You don't have
any money. You don't have any money. You don't have
any money problem because you don't have any
money. My advice to everybody watching is if you're
going to have money problems, don't let it be zero
and make sure it's got a bunch of zeros added to
that one. All right you guys, welcome back.
We have a very special guest today, Grant Cardone.
This is Questions with a Billionaire and Grant, we're
so happy and thankful to be out here in
Miami with you today. Hey, thank you guys
for thinking enough of me and coming out and
introducing me to your audience and hard knocks. I've had
a bunch of them, most of them on my skull,
70 stitches in my head and face when I was 20 years old. I've had a bunch of them,
most of them on my skull, 70 stitches in my head and face when I was 20 years old.
23. Wow. I don't want to do those again. I guess
my first question for you is, in a prior video that I
was seeing you talking about how free time used to
be the devil for you and in today's world you hear
that being busy creates opportunity, but when you
take a look at the modern man today,
they're overweight, they're addicted to a lot
of cheap entertainment, porn, Netflix, all those
things. For someone who really does want to
get their life together and get serious, what's your
best self-improvement tip or advice for people out
there? Boredom is the greatest drug on this
planet. Free time is the greatest... you've got... The
drugs come out the door, you can't break them,
you're not gonna get away with it, and they are you. So
if you do get out of your comfort zone and you have
out there right now pornography um psychiatric drugs all
the add medicines the red i go to the
cocaine dealer and the weed dealer and i don't go to
any of those guys but i would go to them before
i went to your fucking doctor your doctor
is the most dangerous fucking drug dealer on planet
pfizer modern these guys are they're the most lethal
okay i would stay off the drugs off the
porn off the chicks you're a young guy hustling
you leave women alone okay save all that shit
for later get rich every every great looking beautiful
chick in the world want to be with you
if you can get rich enough if you like
chicks okay everybody don't want to be with you become
a billionaire you fucking look better you look
good you're attractive people want to be around
you they want to be around your vibe why because
you got this fucking vibe of success you know how
many times you have to make a million dollars to
become a billionaire dude do the math on that shit
yeah okay people think i'm gonna go from a million
to a billion uh yeah you know how many times you
got to bank a million dollars pay taxes all
the employees keep a margin of it how many times
you got to make a million dollars to become to
keep a billion dollars thousands and thousands of times and
not blow it so you know you need to eat
good you need to take care of yourself and you
need to stay out of no free time because free
time is where drug dealers live free time is
where depression and the devil live okay like i don't
have free time if this place was burning down
right now you ain't gonna be there i'm depressed
i can't leave
if this room gets hot enough you will fucking roll
your ass out of here as fast as you can
so urgency man you want to have urgency in
your schedule the only time i've ever gotten in trouble
in my life right before i got in trouble i
was bored every fucking single time i got in trouble
in my life every time i got bored and
then i compromised the people i was around when you're
bored you compromise you bring the wrong chick home
you get an std you know what i'm talking about
okay okay you know hey man whatever happened you know
what happened to me you know what happened to me
you know what happened to me you know what
happened to me you know what happened to me
not that chlamydia it came on with
you okay so why because you got bored
okay you should have been home dude you
should have been sleeping preparing for the next morning
getting up early go get your workout in get your
hustle on go to breakfast somebody get get get in a
a group a mastermind with some
people that won't put up with that
because people that are hitting playing
on all the cylinders like they're running
and gunning they don't have time for they
don't want the trouble and they're not bored
If you're gonna be bored, dude,
make sure it's on 300 feet.
In a video that you put out,
it's called,
in five steps to becoming a millionaire.
You talked about if you plan
to live on a million dollars,
you're not wealthy, but you're actually worried.
So what would you say
is the most fundamental mindset shift
that people have when it comes to the way
that they look at money?
How old are you?
Yeah, dude, look, a million dollars is not any money.
Like, I mean, a million dollars is no money, okay?
You went from having no money to a million dollars
and now you still have no money.
So I'm just telling you, one emergency, one car wreck,
one cancer treatment, one political event,
another inflation's gonna steal the money.
Like a million dollars for you,
if you had no more
income, a million dollars for you
divided by, let's say, how old are you gonna live?
I'd like to say 80.
Okay, okay, you're gonna live 80 years, okay?
Okay, maybe.
I'd like to say 80.
Divided by, what are you?
21 years old.
So you got, what is that, 59 years?
Okay, divided by 12.
You could spend 1400 bucks
a month on your million dollars.
If there's no inflation, $1400 a month, bro,
that's not even rent.
You can't even go to lunch once.
You ain't strapped a condom on yet, okay?
Nothing, nothing.
You ain't had a bottle, you ain't, like nothing.
You hadn't made one mistake.
That's what you could spend if you never earn
any more income.
So the, you know, first
of all, people have to understand,
man, it takes a lot
of money to have any freedom.
Lot of money, tremendous amounts of money.
And the fact that anybody watching this right now,
you're like, oh my God,
this guy thinks a million dollars
is no money.
I am telling you, it is no money.
Why do you think I'm telling you that?
Cause it's fucking no money.
The only people who think a
million dollars is a lot of money
are people that don't have any money.
So the other thing you guys need to understand is
we all think green is green because somebody told us
it's green, or sweet is sweet because they're telling us,
you know, the answer is green.
You're just gonna be walls.
It's just gonna be walls.
It's just gonna be wall.
because they didn't call it sour if they just
said sweet was sour we'd call it sweet sour
and the only reason we believe a million dollars
a lot of money is because somebody told you that
it was a lot of money and the person that told
you it was a lot of money didn't have a million
dollars you understand yeah because it's not a lot of
money ask cuban if it's a lot of money right
he'd be like uh i can't do anything with a
million dollars nothing so now if you broke you're like oh
that's a lot of that's all the money in
the universe right but it's not true it's just it's
your reference point on it so if you believe that
by the way if you think you're going north and
you're going south you're wrong even though
you believe you're going north you're still wrong
if you think a million dollars a lot of money
and you get it don't be don't be uh shocked when
you're like this is not a lot of money but
that's what you worked for so um last thing i'll
say on this is this okay look if you don't
have any money right now like if you're if you first
of all if you have money problems all
the time you don't have any money you're broke
you should have no opinions about money your
opinion should only be i don't know about money
because i'm doing something wrong with it the
other thing is you got to quit telling people
you got money problems because if you don't
have any money you don't have a money problem
okay because you don't have any money so you got
to quit running around tell me i got a money
problem i got a money right no no you don't
have any money you'll have a money problem when you
have a million dollars that's the only thing you're
going to get with a million dollars is problems
so you get 10 million now you got 10 million
money problems you get to a million problems you're not
hundred million now you got a hundred million
my advice to everybody watching is if you're
gonna have money problems okay don't let it be
zero and make sure it's got a bunch of zeros
added to that one yeah i love it i love it
and then you know the famous quote they say that the
poor get poorer the rich get richer for someone
who may be broke and they're they get wealthy
there you go but they're stuck in that cycle
of poverty what's your advice to someone who is
trying to break that cycle they want to
get really serious about becoming financially free in today's
world yeah so look rich is not wealthy you know
so you got poor you got rich you got wealthy
and in between you got a bunch of just
different variations you've got the middle class a lot of
people stop in the middle class they
go from poverty because your immigrant grandparent
parents came in there they had nothing and now you
got to you earned 70 grand a year oh we're
doing so good compared to my grandpa bro you're
doing so good compared to everybody so but so
what that doesn't mean you can pay your bills
right you get to 140 000 you're like oh my
way you're getting your money back you're getting
your money back you're getting your money back
my god i'm unbelievable you get a job at facebook
you make a 400 grand a year you live in austin
downtown you're like i still don't have any money
so you one you got to quit comparing yourself to
everybody else what i do is i compare myself
to the amount of money on the planet there's 80
trillion dollars 80 trillion bro in circulation so
it's like that's u.s dollars that's not counting
all the other bullshit currencies so i'm like man how
do i get a tiny piece like just a sniff
a whiff a taste just let it visit me for a
second right but but i need it to be enormous amounts
because there's this enormous this poverty
conscious you're talking about you're like
there's a shortage of money no there's not there's
so much money there's more money than there are
people there's more money than there are
telephones there's more money than there like
endless particles of money yeah now if you're
just in this little freaking pocket over here
just looking for the money on the floor oh there's
no money on the floor okay well you're looking in
the wrong place you need to go look where there's
money because it's everywhere and then the second thing
is you you got to attach yourself to people
because you cannot get money there's no money
that will ever come to another human being without
going through another human being i can't you're going to
hold on to your how much money you got on
you right now on me right now yeah what you got
on me just reaching you got nothing i don't have any
cash on me right now you got a credit card
you got something i got some credit cards let me see
your credit card i got you so you see
he's got some money on him okay but but
what's the conduit the via between me and his credit
card is him now two ways to get his credit
card right okay i'm not going to show you these
numbers right here but it's legit but i had to i
had to make contact with him to get his credit card
or i got to wait for him to leave his wallet
someplace and steal it i don't want to steal i'm
not a thief because i can only steal at one time
but if i could you know create a relationship
with you the weight of money there you go
the weight of money you might see 200 already gone
the way the way to the way to
money the way to money is through people
you know it's not through a bank it's not
through even learning something other than i got to learn
how to connect with people even if i'm not or
even if i'm not comfortable with what would you say is
the number one thing that separates the wealthy from
the rich oh yeah well the rich the rich are
just you know they're just just another version of
waiting for the end to come the wealthy bro
there is no end for the wealthy sam walton dies
he founded walmart's uh his he's got five kids that
are on the billionaires list he's only been dead
like 30 years i think they're 15. i think sally
bob uh all the kids are sitting there this is
30 years after he's been dead wealth does not stop
rich stops when you die you pay your estate
taxes the kids split it up money's gone wealthy people
just keeps going so like you go poor i started
out poor i get in the middle class you get tempted
in the middle class air conditioning cars you got
a place to live get a little something on
the weekend you know you got a bottle of
beer you get some entertainment it's a middle class man
middle class it's better off than afghanistan you
know you've got a little something then you
create a little then you get rich you got
a big high paying job now you're paying taxes
you and the husband you and the wife
whatever's working you got a couple kids you
bought your cars but you're getting rich now you
make you got 400 grand a year coming in
people think you're rich you belong to a country
club you got an ira now you're the right
you buy a bigger house you ain't got any you
don't have any freedom you die right now whole
game's off and that's where my dad was my dad
was he died 52 years old bank expires we
were doing great expired whole game was over like
in an instant 72 hours everything changed because
the income stopped okay the decision maker the
ability to go out hunt kill and
bring something home all that stopped that energy
stopped right the brand stopped so what i'm what
i'm doing different than my dad okay and my the
the people that came before me is i'm building out
a brand that will live you know people gonna be
talking about me 50 years from now they won't be
talking about me as much but they'll be now if i
can keep doing something big you know yeah my kids
my kids there's gonna be plenty for them to take
if they want to so they can go to harvard and
get a degree and you know or they could just take my
deal over and they could just take my deal over
and they could just take my deal over and they could
just take my deal over and freaking blow it up
wow and so you became a millionaire at 30 years
old but eventually you became a billionaire what
was the best financial advice that you ever
received throughout your lifetime if there's one lesson
about money that a mentor or somebody taught
you what's the best financial advice you ever
received what's the best financial advice i ever
received um well i don't know i don't know if
it's a piece of advice i received about money look money
Money is just, you know, it's a tool, man.
And I was brought up by, my mother didn't,
she didn't understand money, so
she taught me to manage it.
I learned this doing undercover billionaire, okay?
It wasn't what somebody taught me.
I was put in a
situation where I was given $100.
And they said, you need to use this $100
to build a business.
And I looked at it and I'm
like, okay, how do I do this?
I'm like, well, $100 is not
a way to build a business.
So to go from 100 to 10,
I wanted to build a
$10 million business in 90 days
without using my name.
They dropped me off in Pueblo, Colorado.
So I'm looking at it like a puzzle.
I need to go from 100 to 10 million.
And I'm like, what's the
fastest way to get to zeros?
Because when you're going from 100 to 10 million,
what are you trying to add?
Zeros.
Zeros, that's all you're trying to add.
And I'm like, oh, the fastest way to go there
is to go straight to zero.
Just take the 100 and get rid of it.
So rather than trying to add to it,
I'm like, oh, no, just go to zero.
Got rid of the $100.
I told Discovery, here, take the $100 back.
And they're like, we don't want the $100 back.
I said, take it back.
I don't want it.
I don't need it.
So I basically just go to
zero as fast as I can.
And then I stay at zero the whole time.
And I'm like, OK, I need people.
I don't need money.
Because the tendency is to manage your money.
So the lesson I learned was quit managing money.
OK?
Managers don't make money.
Do you know of a wealthy manager?
No.
Fund manager, Goldman Sachs, they're not managing money.
What are they doing?
They raise money, and then they invest it.
And they raise money, and they invest it.
That's how they make their money.
So go to zero, man.
Don't have any money.
Do not save money.
Don't plan for retirement.
Take every penny you earn from every person you meet
and reinvest that money.
And another thing.
Reinvest it in something that it's your business,
your marketing, your brand, your information.
Getting better, faster, more confident.
Anything that makes you faster, better.
And then when something's left over,
start investing in other real assets.
Obviously, you've built a massive personal brand
for yourself.
And for anyone out there who is aspiring
to do that, to where they can leverage
that in their respective industry and the business
world, what would you tell them?
To build a brand?
Yes.
Build a brand.
You're building one anyway.
Look, I've always been a person that people either liked
or didn't like.
But they knew me.
I don't really care what you call
me.
As long as you call me.
I might not be the best player,
but I'm going to be out there.
I'm going to make some noise.
I'm going to figure it out.
I'm going to get ridiculed for it too.
But I'm going to make some noise.
And if you keep getting out there making noise,
you're going to figure out, OK.
In the beginning, you're going to be awkward,
and you're going to be an idiot, and you're
going to be made fun of.
So the first thing, the
only thing I can do is,
the fucking guy shows up every day.
Last thing I'll tell you.
I remember I was in high school, and I'd
go to this place called The Hungry Night.
I was still born.
I was lost in my life.
And there was this guy.
I don't remember his name right now.
But every Friday, this guy would get in a fight.
Not every other Friday, bro.
Every Friday night.
This guy, about 10.30 at night,
would go out in the back
and fucking throw down with people.
And never won.
OK?
And like, shit, god damn, man.
He'd get up, and he'd get
up, and he'd get beat up down.
And then he'd go back into The Hungry Night
and get drunk again.
Next Friday, bang, same thing.
Third Friday, same thing.
OK?
After a while, people quit fighting that guy.
They're like, hey, that guy.
And he never won the fights.
And he ended up being the most dangerous man
on those weekends.
Because they're like, he's going to fight no matter what.
And I learned from that.
I watch that.
I'm like, OK, I don't want to fight,
because I don't want people hitting on me.
But I'm going to keep showing up.
No matter whether they say good things about me
or bad things about me, whether
I'm good at what I do
or not good, I'm going to
keep showing up until people say,
fucking guy going to keep showing up, bro.
Just step aside.
Leave him alone.
The first deal you ever closed in real estate
was only one unit.
And the second deal that you closed was 38 units.
What was the biggest mindset shift
that enabled you to, in your second deal,
close over 37 more than your first deal?
The first deal was a single family.
Second deal was a single family.
The third deal was 48 units.
So it was one, a single.
28 days later, I closed another single.
Three years later, I would buy 48 units.
That 48 units made me a multimillionaire.
I made $3.7 million net net on that deal.
Took the 3.7.
I put 350 grand in that
deal in the third deal I did.
What happened on the first two deals
was there was a little bit of cash flow.
They were cool.
But I'm like, OK, this is not going to scale.
A lot of the guys, a
lot of the coaches and educators
on Instagram and social media, they don't scale.
They're doing good.
They got cars, nice cars.
And they got a big house.
And all that looks good.
But it's not scaling.
Amazon scales, right?
So when I bought those first two,
houses, I realized, oh, they can't scale.
And the way I learned it was this chick, Janet,
let's say this was a house, 1117 Sheffield Street,
Bel Air, Texas.
She moved in.
Janet moved in.
She paid me.
When she moved out, there was no money.
And so I didn't know
that until I did the deals.
So I'm like, oh, what's the way to solve that?
Don't buy one unit.
So my third deal, it took three years.
I learned.
I went and started spending time and energy and resources
on learning real estate.
Then once I knew what I was looking
for, bang, I saw that deal, 48 units.
I raised the money for it.
I raised $350,000 to buy it.
I signed a note for $1.9 million, easiest loan
I ever got in my life.
I had no credit, by the way, no money.
And I made $3.7 million.
Changed my life.
The first deal, even the single family,
when I made $200 of cash
flow a month, that changed my life.
I'm like, oh, there's other ways
to make money other than just
being a sales guy.
But that third deal, that third
deal was like, OK, I just made
$3.6 million, $3.7 million on one deal.
If I do that 10 times, I'll make $37 million.
I'll have $37 million.
And at that time, I'm 31 years old.
I'm thinking, shit, I'm going
to be a multimillionaire one day.
I'm going to be worth tens of millions of dollars.
I'm not thinking I'm going to end up with 12,000
of these units and 20-plus businesses.
I'm not thinking about the internet, social media,
or you're going to come along
and put me on your hard knock
show and make me a damn.
You know, give me some more haters.
What would you tell the
people that want to get started
in real estate today?
What's that first step that people should take to start
paying well?
You need a commitment.
You need to quit making all these excuses.
What you need is commitment.
If you have a commitment,
you don't have a money problem.
So it's not true.
You're just telling them, oh, I need a credit score.
No.
You buy 48 units, and they
earn $48,000 a month in income.
They make $1,000.
Your loan's not going to even
be based on your credit score.
So like, when I buy a piece of real estate,
I'm going to make $3,000.
They're not lending me the money.
The bank doesn't lend Grant the money.
The bank lends the LLC, the apartment complex.
The 48-unit apartment complex LLC
is what gets the loan, not
me.
I'm not even responsible for the loan.
So you guys out there are
like, I got to have a loan.
I don't even have a credit score.
I don't know what my credit score is.
My credit score is like 5.1.
Would it be?
I mean, I don't have $2,000 in my credit score.
My credit score is, what's your credit score?
I don't know.
How about that one?
That's my credit score.
How about, I don't know, 12,000
units paying me 2 grand a month.
That's my credit score.
My credit score is I got $450,000 coming in
off the internet every morning.
That's my credit score.
Like, I don't know a credit score.
I ain't got a credit score.
Wealthy people don't have credit scores.
They got assets.
So the first thing people have to commit
to is not how they can't do it.
I'm committed to getting real estate.
Don't worry about where the money's going to come from.
If you're committed to becoming wealthy, you
can't figure out how to do it first.
This is what's wrong with our education system.
They should not put people in 12 years
of school and then four years of college.
You should just teach people, dude, what do
you want to do on this planet, okay?
Like, if every American, their only thing was, I'm
going to create a billion dollars in net worth.
If every American did that,
imagine what our country would do.
Dude, we would be the
superpower of all superpowers, superpowers forever.
Because every kid now wouldn't
be worried about history or English.
They'd be like, let me just study how
to create a billion dollars worth of net worth.
And how do you do that?
Well, you've got to tie in to
8 billion people, servicing 8 billion people.
This is what I tell them.
Like, you don't, how do I service people, right?
And then health care.
Cosmetics.
The pornography industry was just created.
There's no great product or service there.
There's no, all they did
was give people what they wanted.
You know?
And it's terrible that people even
have that much time to do that.
Right?
Or drugs, alcohol, the same thing.
Stripper joints, tattoos.
I mean, tattoos are, what
did I see the other day?
The lottery business, okay?
Last year, what do you think this
country spends on lottery tickets a year?
Just give me any number.
Let me see.
A big number.
Yeah.
It's 330 million people in America.
Yeah, I'll say 10 billion.
105 billion.
That is more money than every sporting
event, every music download, every live concert,
and every...
movie produced in this country.
Lottery tickets.
Wow, people want to win something.
Right?
I want to get lucky.
Well, you're not going to get lucky.
You have a better chance of becoming a
millionaire in America than you do having visible abs.
Three million people in America have visible abs.
You're not one of them.
I am.
Okay?
Okay.
You're one of three million.
But, do you?
Let me see them.
You want me to?
Show them, bro.
It's your channel.
Let me see.
You have visible abs?
Yeah.
He does, dude.
That's one of three million.
Okay?
Do you know you have seven...
The people watching have seven times, 7x
better chance of becoming a millionaire than having
visible abs.
I believe it.
Three million Americans have visible abs.
22 million Americans have...
Are millionaires.
I don't know how many billionaires there are.
But when I started looking at billionaires,
I'm like, okay, how many are there?
Bing.
Okay?
If there's 10 of them, what do they do?
All I'm gonna do is
go track what that cat did.
You know?
If you wanna go fishing out here, okay?
You get in a boat.
I'm gonna tell you a story
about yacht life here in a second.
You get in a boat and you're
going out there and you're running around.
Your boat captain's going around.
He's looking for fish.
What's he gonna look for?
What's he gonna look for to find fish?
He's gonna have his little navigation system,
his little freaking fish finder in there and
all the bullshit, calling into other boats.
But he's gonna see six
or eight boats over here, right?
And he's gonna see seagulls, right?
And he's gonna see a lot of fish.
Dude, that's where the fish are.
Go over there!
Just follow the damn traffic.
You know.
But some arrogant captain's gonna be like, no,
I'm reading my school system and I got
all my technology.
Bro, the boats are over there.
I'll tell you a story.
I was in the south of France.
I'm on a 208 boat.
I got a boat that was
a little bit bigger than me.
I was trying to get a boat.
I got a boat.
The boat's right over there.
I'll tell you a story.
I was in the south of France.
I'm on a 208 foot, totally bragging
right now, 208 foot, um, Benete yacht.
And me and my, my
family on there for two weeks.
And we're, we're finding a place to go
to this new island we're going to in Sardinia,
actually.
We left France, going to Sardinia and, and
we pull up and the captain's bringing me to
this place.
I'm like, bro, look, I got
this thing called Marine, uh, app.
And I'm like, bro, I've been
to this place for a while.
the marine app on my on my phone and so i
could see all the other players around me these are all
big boats 300 foot 250 280 360 foot i'm like
bro look see this there's a there's all the boats
anywhere everywhere in the world okay and i happen to
be over here in this part of the world at the
time and so i'm tracking these boats i'm like
that's jeff pieces bro bro that's 360 feet it's
a goddamn sailboat there's two people on it he's got
a staff of 42 people to service two people on
a 360 foot boat that is longer than a football
field you understand and behind that boat is a 250
foot supply boat with helicopter landing pad on both
of course okay so that jeff and his new wife
can fly to the little restaurant that they want to
go to okay now next to him is frank partita's boat
who won yacht of the year got an award it's
240 foot it looks like it's 400. it's the yacht of
the year but it's not the yacht of the year it's
the boat of the year it's the boat of the year
it's designed unbelievable and behind him is the
damn king of saudi arabia's boat okay now these
guys these guys are literally like i'm looking at
like okay that that's 300 million behind it's 150
million there's 200 million we got we have over
a billion dollars worth of boat we have jeff's got
180 million dollars of network frank fatina's got
probably i don't know 40 50 million dollars
that's a quarter of a trillion
yeah and then we got the the
king of saudi so what are we talking about
i mean we're talking about endless amounts of wealth
my captain wants to pass these guys
because he's got a better place to park
okay he's like grant man where we're going is
man there's no waves i'm not a marine guy i'm
not a sailor i'm not a captain i don't know
anything i'm just me you know i know my my
iq comes from you know the bayous i got a lot
my con my common common sense iq is probably off the
books and my bro why are we going any
place you just passed jeff frank in the king okay
he puts the anchor down he's like no no i
got a better place i said there ain't no way
in the world my world your world their world any
world that you're going to be in a better place
than what we just passed it's impossible you
don't know anything about winds and waters and
waves i'm saying whatever bro impossible that we're
in a better place he puts the anchor down
As soon as he puts the anchor down, all
these little gnats show up because it was too steel.
You've got to have a little bit of wind, right?
I said, bro, pull the anchor
up and go back to the money.
It's called follow the money.
And you don't have to be
a sailor to know this shit.
Go back to where the money is.
Do you think anybody's on Jeff's boat that's going
to put him in anything other than the best place?
No.
Impossible.
He's got 28 staff on
one boat, 22 on another boat.
For Tita's got 22 people.
The king of Saudi probably got fucking 17
wives on that boat and another 28 staff.
I'm like, just common sense, man.
Follow the money.
You don't need to be a sailor.
Hey, guys, we hope you're
enjoying this interview with Grant Cardone.
And we'll be back to it in a second.
But we have a very special announcement for you.
We always get asked by you guys, how
can we connect with these people that you're interviewing?
And we want to let our
YouTube family know first before anybody else.
We just launched our Discord.
This community is completely free.
So you don't want to miss out on the opportunity to
build and connect with like-minded individuals on the journey of self-improvement.
We will have a ton of free resources available
for you to improve your business, career, and overall lifestyle.
You'll also have the opportunity to become a premier Discord member where you can access and watch all
of our exclusive and uncut interviews with business moguls like Grant Cardone and other 8, 9, and 10-figure entrepreneurs.
We're also going to be hosting live calls with 8 and 9-figure entrepreneurs across a
variety of booming industries where you can meet and ask them questions about your business.
We'll see you in a couple of weeks.
Bye.
If you don't scale, you're
not going to, you have nothing.
You don't have a business.
You're basically somebody else's bitch.
Probably even your own.
Like, there's no such thing as being
the boss, just so you guys know.
The smaller the company is,
the more bitch you are, really.
The more controlled you are, the more,
you know, if you have three employees,
they're going to push you around,
even though you're writing the checks.
If you have 30 customers,
they're going to push you around
because you can't lose customers.
You've got to scale so that you can lose customers.
You have to scale your
employees so that you can, like,
you're never dependent upon an employee.
You know, if you have
three employees, you've got a problem.
You've got 30 employees, you still have a problem.
If you've got 3,000 employees, you don't have a problem.
You don't have a problem.
You don't have 3,000 problems.
You have a manager or two that has 3,000 problems,
but you don't have them anymore.
That's why you've got to scale.
So my first business couldn't scale.
It was in a very tiny vertical,
and I was the authority in the vertical.
I was the king of the vertical.
So it appeared on paper that I was,
compared to how my dad did or my grandparents,
I was doing phenomenal, but it was not scalable.
I couldn't sell it.
I couldn't exit it.
I had to do everything,
and now we're in 10x health.
That thing's scalable to the
hundreds of billions of dollars.
We're in real estate.
I've raised a billion dollars in cash there.
That business has got $5 billion worth of real estate.
That could go to $10 billion, $50 billion.
It could go to $100 billion.
Like, there's no limit.
As much as I can imagine, as
long as I can add good people,
it can grow and scale there.
A big component, like you said,
was bringing the right people in.
What's the number one trait
that you look for in someone?
Yeah.
No, no, not them being successful.
You've got to be successful.
Success attracts success.
You know, when an NBA team
wins, dude, they can get winners.
Like, if they've got a chance
of winning the ring next year,
all the players, the champions, are going
to want to go to that team.
So you guys that are having trouble,
hiring people, number one, because you're too small.
Number two, because you haven't done anything.
Number three, because you've got an idea.
Everybody's got ideas.
By the way, the great
ideas go to the great first.
The great ideas end up in
the graveyard before all the ideas do.
And then you never, even when you get somebody good,
you don't keep them because you're small.
No great person is going to
want to hang out with three people.
To keep great people, something needs to get big.
And so notice Tom Brady.
Tom Brady, I mean, is the GOAT, right?
So he leaves, what does he do?
He becomes a partner in a football team.
So you see what I'm saying is
he left the game and got bigger, right?
Most people, most people just, there's no place to go.
You got to have a place to go.
So if you want great people around,
number one, you got to do great shit.
Two, you got to quit doing dumb shit.
Okay, because if you're going to
the strip joints on the weekends,
or the clubs, or popping
bottles, nobody does business popping bottles.
You know, you're just not going to
make any money after 10 o'clock at night.
Right.
And if you've got to make
money, you're going to make money.
Right. And if you've got to
make money, you're going to make money.
And if you guys think partying at two o'clock
in the morning is going to get you a deal,
it'll never get you a deal.
I've been doing this game 40 years.
I've never got a deal after nine o'clock at night.
Wow.
And so get, you know, do something
successful because people want to be around me.
You know, when I do an
event, it's got 34,000 people in it.
They're like, God damn.
Like I can get almost any speaker in
the world now because our events are so big
and we sell out every event I do.
Why?
Because the other ones were so
successful that people now trust me.
Right.
They trust me and be like,
okay, who's going to bring this year?
Successful.
Success is the way to attract great people.
And you've sold.
It's not a pay plan.
It's not incentives.
It's not days off.
It's not a big office.
Fucking be successful and people
will want to be around you.
And then when they leave, they're
going to be like, oh shit, Grant.
Grant was an asshole.
Grant's a hard guy.
He didn't give me enough attention.
I didn't make enough money.
You're going to go to the
next place and nothing's going on.
You're gonna be like, fuck, I wish I
was back over there because at least they had,
at least something was happening.
You've sold billions of dollars
in revenue throughout your career.
Yeah.
How have you been able to consistently close massive deals?
What is Grant Cardone's secret to sales?
80% of everything we do here is free.
Now the 20% that pay me, you
know, this year will pay me $150 million.
But the 80% got, got
a billion dollars worth of advice.
They just didn't pay me anything,
but they came into my funnel, right?
They came into my, okay,
now I know who they are.
Can I serve them when they're ready to pay something?
Not everybody's ready to pay, right?
So like when I was a kid, man, I
said, I wouldn't pay for anything because they didn't have
any money.
So if, if I went, you know,
if you walk into a casino invasion,
you know, in Vegas, you can walk
in, you don't have to have money.
All you gotta do is walk in.
Everything's free.
So my world, I'm a
big open casino, like everything's free.
Now, when you get in, you're like, shit, you
know, I'd like to sit at that table with the
whales.
Well, then that costs something or I want
to sit over this table with the hundred dollar
players or I want to go
over here and play this game.
Well, to do that, then you got
to sit down and you got to pay.
So we've raised 1.1 billion
dollars crowdfunding on the internet.
I don't go to wealthy people.
I don't go to Mark Cuban
and say, hey, fund my project.
I've never gone to a big equity fund like
a Blackstone and say, give me a million billion
dollars.
I could but I don't I
go to build a big audience.
I create great products and offers and then I
go to that always say, would you guys like
to invest with me?
So out of we I think we have 450,000
people in an investor that raised their hand said,
I'm interested in your investments.
13,000 of the 400,000 invested with me.
Not all of them.
Whatever percentage.
That is.
Probably less than 2% and and what is that percentage?
Anyway, out of 450,000 13,000.
I don't know.
It's tiny, right?
13,000 divided by 450,000.
Yeah, 0.28% to put all of them should
have invested with me 2.8% were smart enough to
do it.
97% missed out on deals.
We have.
Last year.
I had 154,000 people buy product
from me not invest with me.
They bought a product or service ticket event something.
I have 16 million people online that
all got the same information by the way.
So less than 1 10th of 1% bought
anything from me still still made 155 million dollars
and you wrote a book called the closer survival guy.
Yeah, what is your best advice to anybody
that may struggle with closing in today's world?
You know, you need to change your mind about
closing people closing people is when you service them.
For the first time you guys need to understand that when
you close a deal when somebody actually buys your product service.
Offer whatever your offer is.
That's when you finally service them.
I don't think about the clothes being I got you.
I got you.
You know, I don't think about it being that
I think a lot of salespeople think I got you.
You know, no, I didn't get you dude.
I finally I finally serviced you when I close you by the way, that should be
the first close that should be of the hundred and fifty four thousand people that bought something.
For me last year 45,000 of them have bought three four five six seven eight things like 30% of our and I want to get the other 70% to make
sure that's not the first thing and the only thing they buy from you for people that may not know like what was the biggest turning point in your life.
Where's he come up with all this shit man?
This guy's good man.
Thank you.
We've been doing this a long time.
I guess I'll ask you know for people that may not know at one point
in time in your life, you know, you were pursuing baseball and that didn't work out.
Oh man, you know that story.
I'm kind of.
You know, fallen into drugs and the wrong crowd.
Yeah, wrong crowd.
What was the turning point in your life that really enabled you to get
your life on track and you eventually became a billionaire 10 years to lose it.
That's what that's a turning around.
You guys get sick and tired of losing.
Then you're like, okay, I'm gonna change everything.
I changed all my friends.
Changed everywhere.
I went.
Gave up a girlfriend gave up all the buddies.
Quit going to those places.
You swallowed a bunch of pride.
Had to go back out and face people made amends probably three
years took me three years to clean up all the damage I created.
And then I had to get good at something.
So you can't just clean up and not change.
You got to clean up and then
you got to like start contributing back.
So for probably from the age of 25 till I
was 28 years old good three and a half years.
All I did every single day.
Without exaggeration.
Showed up at work early and I stayed late.
I was the first one
there and the last one leave.
I can't man.
There's not a day anybody
that was hanging out with me.
It'll tell you dude the guy every day.
When we were closed on Sundays, I'd show
up because I had nothing else to do.
Free time was the devil.
And so I was either working on myself
or I was trying to help somebody else.
That's all I did or I was sleeping.
I was either learning or sleep helping or sleeping.
And I don't talk about that a bunch but you know and today what that what that did was that really built
a discipline, you know today like if you look at my life today if somebody was simply look at my life today.
I don't do I don't
like do a bunch of stuff.
I come to work and help people.
I come to work and I have great work ethic and I help people and
and I you know, and I try not to get bored because when I get bored.
Even today.
Dude, even today like I got a call with Jamie
Foxx his somebody from his place called this years ago.
Hey, Jamie's having a birthday party.
I was in Vegas you in Vegas.
I see you're in Vegas.
You want to go to his birthday party?
I said, yeah, that sounds great, man.
I'm in Vegas by myself.
And I said, when is it?
He's like show up show up at the such
a nice club at 2 30 in the morning.
I'm like, yeah, I won't be showing up there, bro.
2 30 in the morning.
No, nothing good happened to
anybody 2 30 in the morning.
Yeah, especially a guy like me.
So if you're sick and tired of being sick and
tired, you know, yummy, you got to get sick and tired.
Now you guys don't need you
just need to manufacture sick and tired.
You don't need to hit the bottom this
whole thing about I got to hit bottom.
No, you don't most of you guys hit the bottom a long time
ago and you just getting drugged down the bottom could keep going down.
By the way, if you just look at the ocean.
There's it can keep going down as deep as you want, you know, unless you just want
to hope to die because it can go deep and then deeper and then worse and then worse.
Or there's a lot of levels of bad.
So, you know, I would I would I
would tell you to do is trick yourself.
What I do today is I
trick myself to be a motivated.
I tricked myself into being disgusted with myself.
And so that's why I go look at just boat.
And like I'm a 360 feet where that thing cost.
What's it cost to manage it?
What does it cost to keep it?
How many people on board?
Okay, with the boat behind it, the helicopter on it.
The guy's got a basketball court on a boat, bro.
I'm like, dang, man.
I can't even shoot.
But I want to have a basketball court
on the back of a of a boat.
I mean, I'm like, what's that cost?
What's it take to do that?
How many people would have to
meet and I start doing the math.
I play with my phone
all the time doing the math.
Well, because that keeps me busy.
It's not really about the money.
It's about the game.
It's I want a game of
production, not a game of destruction.
And so everybody can do better.
I know that I know everybody believes
that nobody's going to disagree with that.
Concept.
You might not like me,
but you're not going to disagree.
Everyone can do a little better.
Maybe that much better.
And and if you can, you should.
And and for me, money is very, very important.
Having money is like so important.
And it might not be
important to you to have money.
But the moment the local school or hospital or kid or your
parents need something like everybody's underestimating how much money it takes to really.
Do well.
Or maybe.
Maybe your church, the church or something
that you feel really strong about needs money.
Nobody takes happy moments.
You know, you don't go to Whole Foods and
say, get four bags because your family needs to eat.
And they're like, hey, we're taking happy today.
No, no, they're not taking happy, dude.
They're taking US dollars, credit cards.
They want money.
And so the fact that any human being
has to say no because you don't have it.
You don't have it because you didn't do it.
Or you did it.
And then you got irresponsible with it.
Like, I've never been irresponsible with money.
You know, that's not been my downfall.
I had a lot of downfalls, but that wasn't one.
I bank it.
And one of my downfalls
was I didn't use it correctly.
I saved it.
I just stored it, stacked it
over and over and over again.
That's what I would tell the young guys to man.
I wouldn't stack money at all.
I would grab it, take it, either
invest in yourself or in your business.
But at some point you want to
quit investing in you in the business.
You want to invest in a third thing.
You want to invest in some real asset, something outside
of this thing that you're doing between you and your business.
Invest in what do you guys live?
Austin?
Yes, start buying real estate.
Next 18 months is going to be
the greatest real estate opportunity in your lifetime.
Maybe for the next 50 years.
You know, bank your money, dude, and go buy
as much real estate as you can in Austin.
It's going to be on sale.
You're going to buy stuff for 40%
less than what the last guy paid.
It's going to be like, it's going to be unbelievable.
So anyway, that's what I tell people, man.
You got to.
You guys can do more than you can do.
You don't believe me.
You know, go listen to your other uncle.
Yeah, you know, he ain't done nothing.
You got to listen to Uncle G though.
But I think that that wraps up
today's episode guys of questions with a billionaire.
Grant, thank you so much for being with us today.
Appreciate you, man.
Appreciate you guys.
You guys are awesome.
Conversation and everybody go tapping with Grant
Cardone and the school of Hardin XX Grant.
Let's go.
Thank you, man.
Cool.